Dallas Smythe fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Publications and presentations, 1936 - 1992; F-16-6; 1.77 m of textual records; Physical description: 7 photographs located in F-16-6-2-1
  - Publications and presentations, 1936 - 1992; F-16-6-1; 1.52 m of textual records
    - Royal Commission on Broadcasting - report, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-62 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Royal Commission on Broadcasting - programme analysis, 1957; F-16-6-1-0-63 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Menace of pay TV, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-64 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Our Canadian lesson on TV/radio, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-65 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - American culture in the shadow of the satellites, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-66 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The human image in TV, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-67 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The meaning of the communications revolution, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-68 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Attitudes toward the frontiers of faith - Conversation Piece TV series, June-July 1958 - a pilot study, F-16-6-1-0-69 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The cultural context of religion and the mass media, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-70 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Toward more effective educational TV: a pilot study of the effects of commercial TV on the verbal behaviour of pre-school children, 1958; F-16-6-1-0-71 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Space satellite communications and public opinion, 1959; F-16-6-1-0-72 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Suburbia today - 1959 market survey, F-16-6-1-0-73 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Christianity and television, 1959; F-16-6-1-0-74 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The bias of time in the cultural context of the mass media, 1959 - 1960; F-16-6-1-0-75 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Controlling the broadcast mass media, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-76 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Report to the president on sabbatical study, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-77 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Libertarian press doctrine: the puritan revolution context, [ca 1960]; F-16-6-1-0-78 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Taste, social class, commuting and volume of mass media use in suburban communities, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-79 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The responsibility of the mass media in war and peace, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-80 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - On the political economy of communications, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-81 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - International radio structure and policy, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-82 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Memorandum on basic education by radio in under-developed countries, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-83 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - Outline of a proposal for competitive U.S. broadcast systems, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-84 (Archival box - standard 16-33)
    - The spiral of terror and the mass media, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-85 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Space satellite communications and public opinion, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-86 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Space satellite broadcasting: threat or promise?, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-87 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Space satellite broadcasting and international organization for radio, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-88 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - The modern media man and the political process, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-89 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public issues programs on three television and two radio stations, 1960; F-16-6-1-0-90 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - The problem of communication of falsehood in broadcasting: ethics, goals, techniques, effects, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-91 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Communications satellites, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-92 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Les mass media et la politique etrangere, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-93 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Let's live in the world, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-94 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Das bild des politikers in den massenmedien, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-95 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - The serviceability of the mass media and other arts in a nuclear age, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-96 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Persuasion as a cultural phenomenon, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-97 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - The mass media and foreign policy making in the Cold War, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-98 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Review of Anti-Trust in the Motion Picture Industry," and Broadcast regulation and joint ownership of media", 1961; F-16-6-1-0-99 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Testimony of Dallas W. Smythe before the Monopoly Sub-committee, Senate Small Business Committee, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-100 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Statement on communications (at Athens conference), 1961; F-16-6-1-0-101 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public issues programs on two local radio stations, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-102 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public issues programs on three television and two radio stations, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-103 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public issues programs on three television and four radio stations, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-104 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public issues programs on seventeen television and thirty-six radio stations, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-105 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Public benefit or private privilege: the debate on ownership of communications satellites, 1961; F-16-6-1-0-106 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Mass media and the churches, 1961 - 1962; F-16-6-1-0-107 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - How to start a peace race, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-108 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Material for Senator Long in filibuster on communications satellite legislation, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-109 (Archival box - standard 16-34)
    - Report on effect of deintermixture in Peoria, Springfield, and related areas of Illinois, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-110 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Conference on the problem of international communication, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-111 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Communications satellites (letter to the editor of Science), 1962; F-16-6-1-0-112 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Breaking through the thought barrier to survival, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-113 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Outthinking ourselves, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-114 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Time, market, and space factors in communications economics, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-115 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Statement before Senate Judiciary Committee, Anti-trust and Monopoly Subcommittee, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-116 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Memorandum on audience studies submitted by Atlas Broadcasting Company and Grand Broadcasting Company, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-117 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Considerations on a world wide communications satellite system, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-118 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Cuban crisis: a failure in our definition of reality, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-119 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Analysis of ownership of television stations in top 75 markets, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-120 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Channel 4, Bloomington, Illinois report, 1962; F-16-6-1-0-121 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Reply to opposition to petition for reconsideration (Dallas Smythe as expert witness), 1963; F-16-6-1-0-122 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Institutional factors in Cold War policy, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-123 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Brainrinsing, bipartisanship, and dictatorship vs. peace, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-124 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - The Churches, the mass media, and peace, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-125 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Review of The Decline of Cinema, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-126 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Peace in a shrinking world, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-127 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - The mass media today and tomorrow, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-128 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Review of The Religious Press in America, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-129 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Review of The Improper Opinion, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-130 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Mass media and the cold war, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-131 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - University High School commencement address, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-132 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Change and the mass media of communications, 1963; F-16-6-1-0-133 (Archival box - standard 16-35)
    - Reader's report on Smythe's book, A Content Analysis..., 1964; F-16-6-1-0-134 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Violence, sex, censorship, freedom, and broadcasting, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-135 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Report to the University of Illinois Research Board (study of relations of the American and European communications industries), 1964; F-16-6-1-0-136 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Testimony - national communications system, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-137 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Die massenmedien heute und morgen, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-138 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Adult education begins in the first grade, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-139 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - On thinking about the effects of communications satellites, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-140 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Testimony - Federal Communications Commission domestic telegraph investigation, 1964; F-16-6-1-0-141 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Orbiting bombs and the Manned Orbiting Laboratories (letter to the editor of Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), 1964; F-16-6-1-0-142 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - The citizen and the mass media of communications, 1965; F-16-6-1-0-143 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Satellite broadcasting by the United Nations family of organizations, 1965; F-16-6-1-0-144 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Section 2 - what is the situation in which communications satellites pose their problem, 1965; F-16-6-1-0-145 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - On the effects of communications satellites, 1965; F-16-6-1-0-146 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Review of Television and Society - an Inquest and Agenda for Improvement, 1965; F-16-6-1-0-147 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Domestic telegraph service report, 1966; F-16-6-1-0-148 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - What place is there for graduates of 1966 in today's society?, F-16-6-1-0-149 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Alcoholism as a symptom of social disorder: an ecological view, 1966; F-16-6-1-0-150 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Freedom of information: some analysis and a proposal for satellite broadcasting, 1966; F-16-6-1-0-151 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - The political and economic conditions of freedom of information, 1967; F-16-6-1-0-152 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Trade union- labour management course, 1967; F-16-6-1-0-153 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - Education for citizenship seminar, 1967; F-16-6-1-0-154 (Archival box - standard 16-36)
    - The language of the moving image, 1967; F-16-6-1-0-155 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Comment - H.L. Black, French and Canadian political journalists: a comparative study, 1967; F-16-6-1-0-156 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Assessment of H. Carsch application to Canada Council, 1968; F-16-6-1-0-157 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Comments on "The Church and the Media of Mass Communication", 1968; F-16-6-1-0-158 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Manufacturing public opinion, 1968; F-16-6-1-0-159 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Conflict, cooperation, and communications satellites (English and Spanish versions), 1968 - 1969; F-16-6-1-0-160 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Conciliation - Smeeds (Regina) labour dispute, 1969; F-16-6-1-0-161 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Popular culture: mythmaker and brainwasher (English and Spanish versions), 1969; F-16-6-1-0-162 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Buy something - five myths of consumership, 1969; F-16-6-1-0-163 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Remarks at conference on the legal problems of international communications: panel in Intelsat, 1969 - 1970; F-16-6-1-0-164 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Mass media, youth, and the classroom, 1970; F-16-6-1-0-165 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Study 1(e) - the relevance of United States legislative - regulatory experience to the Canadian telecommunications situation, 1970; F-16-6-1-0-166 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Toward goal-oriented critical research for communications media, 1970; F-16-6-1-0-167 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Cultural realism and cultural screens, 1971; F-16-6-1-0-168 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - The political character of science (including communication science), or science is not ecumenical, 1971; F-16-6-1-0-169 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Review of The Medium is the Rear View Mirror: Understanding McLuhan, 1971; F-16-6-1-0-170 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Brief note on a visit to 800 million people, 1972; F-16-6-1-0-171 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Chile: an end to cultural colonialism, 1972; F-16-6-1-0-172 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - The "Orbital parking slot" syndrome and radio frequency management, 1972; F-16-6-1-0-173 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Reflections on proposals for an international programme of communications research, 1972; F-16-6-1-0-174 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Mass communications and cultural realism: the experience of China, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-175 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Whom are you neutral against? communications media and social values in China, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-176 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Status of University of Saskatchewan statement, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-177 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - After bicycles, what?, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-178 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - The Basic concerns which support positive program controls for direct broadcast satellites, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-179 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - Memorandum on some questions regarding telecommunications development in British Columbia, 1973; F-16-6-1-0-180 (Archival box - standard 16-37)
    - The Yugoslavian road toward capitalism, 1974; F-16-6-1-0-181 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - A study of Saskatchewan telecommunications, 1974; F-16-6-1-0-182 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Television traffic - a one-way street? (UNESCO report), 1974; F-16-6-1-0-183 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Role of the mass media and popular culture in defining development, 1974; F-16-6-1-0-184 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Rate adjustment formula as proposed for communications carriers by the Canadian Transport Commission - report of a study, 1975; F-16-6-1-0-185 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Report on financial disclosure by cable television broadcasting undertakings as it relates to rate applications, 1975; F-16-6-1-0-186 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - TV media: a commodity to sell commodity system, 1975; F-16-6-1-0-187 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Socialist and capitalist realism in the arts and sciences: a systemic view, 1976; F-16-6-1-0-188 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Telecommunications Equipment Inquiry - Restrictive Trade Practices Commission (folder 1), 1977; F-16-6-1-0-189 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Telecommunications Equipment Inquiry - Restrictive Trade Practices Commission (folder 2), 1977; F-16-6-1-0-190 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - Canadian communications: media of cultural submission, 1977; F-16-6-1-0-191 (Archival box - standard 16-38)
    - You people as communications commodity, 1977; F-16-6-1-0-192 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Critique of The Consciousness Industry, 1977; F-16-6-1-0-193 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Communications: blindspot of western Marxism, 1977; F-16-6-1-0-194 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Discussion for the SFU conference on H.A. Innis, 1978; F-16-6-1-0-195 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of Herbert I. Schiller's Communication and Cultural Domination, 1978; F-16-6-1-0-196 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of The Media are American, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-197 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Interview at Shanghai Advertising Corporation, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-198 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Discussion at regulation conference, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-199 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Issues in international communications: people, commodities, and political processes, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-200 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Economic analysis and radio spectrum fees: the microwave band, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-201 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Lecture on Mongolia, 1979; F-16-6-1-0-202 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - The level and structure of license fees in the microwave band, 1980; F-16-6-1-0-203 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Statement in support of comments of the office of communications, United Church of Christ (radio deregulation), 1980; F-16-6-1-0-204 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of The Public Eye: Television and the Politics of Canadian Broadcasting, 1952-1968, 1980; F-16-6-1-0-205 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - The electronic information tiger: on the political economy of the radio spectrum and the Third World interest, 1980; F-16-6-1-0-206 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Idealism vs. realism in international communications: a review essay, 1981; F-16-6-1-0-207 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of Does Mass Communications Change Public Opinion After All?, 1981; F-16-6-1-0-208 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Policy on information and ideology: the spiral of terror (Part 2), 1981; F-16-6-1-0-209 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Communications: blindspot of economics, 1981; F-16-6-1-0-210 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - On thinking the unthinkable about nuclear war and its consequences for the peace movement, 1981; F-16-6-1-0-211 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - On rationalizing the relation of private and public sectors: deregulation of radio in the 1980s, 1981; F-16-6-1-0-212 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Communications "technology" and the Third World, 1982; F-16-6-1-0-213 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of Mass Media and the Revolutionary Movement, and Marx and Engels on the Means of Communications, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-214 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - On critical theory and the political economy of communications, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-215 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - World communications year: reality and theory on the information age, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-216 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - On the political economy of C3I, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-217 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Adjusting to new market structures in telecommunications, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-218 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - On critical and administrative research: a new critical analysis, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-219 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Universal service and the access charge debate, 1983; F-16-6-1-0-220 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Comments on The Mass Media and Communications Systems in the Soviet Union, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-221 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - National Policy on Public and Private Sectors, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-222 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - The radio spectrum, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-223 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Review of Communication and Class Struggle 2 - Liberation, Socialism, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-224 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - New directions for critical communications research, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-225 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Capitalism, advertising, and the consciousness industry, 1984; F-16-6-1-0-226 (Archival box - standard 16-39)
    - Communication, information, and culture - annotated bibliography, 1985; F-16-6-1-0-227 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Factors affecting the Canadian and U.S. spectrum management processes: a preliminary evaluation, 1985; F-16-6-1-0-228 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Needs before tools - the illusions of technology, 1985; F-16-6-1-0-229 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Training programme - International Telecommunications Union conferences, 1985; F-16-6-1-0-230 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Review article/ One Canadian perspective: clear across Australia, 1985; F-16-6-1-0-231 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - An historical perspective on equity: national policy on public and private sectors in the U.S.A., 1985; F-16-6-1-0-232 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Culture, communication "technology" and Canadian policy (includes French and English versions), 1986; F-16-6-1-0-233 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - El perill de la informació electrònica o l'economia política de les freqüències de ràdio: i l'interès del tercer món, 1986; F-16-6-1-0-234 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Ideology, culture, and technology, 1986; F-16-6-1-0-235 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Radio spectrum policy and world needs, 1986; F-16-6-1-0-236 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - International communications in the International Year of Peace, 1986; F-16-6-1-0-237 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - High tech: who wins, who loses?, 1987; F-16-6-1-0-238 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Freedom is the act of resisting necessity, 1987 - 1988; F-16-6-1-0-239 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Communications: blindspot of the social sciences, 1988; F-16-6-1-0-240 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Unsaintly alliance Against New International Information and Communication Order (NIICO), 1988; F-16-6-1-0-241 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Europe for Europeans: a conspectus, 1988; F-16-6-1-0-242 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - The information society culture: what and whose choices?, or, on to globalization, 1988; F-16-6-1-0-243 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Memo to Bill Melody - Centre for International Research on Communications and Information Technology (CIRCIT), 1989; F-16-6-1-0-244 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Television deregulation and the public, 1989; F-16-6-1-0-245 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Foreword to Canadian dreams and American control: political economy of the Canadian feature film industry, 1990; F-16-6-1-0-246 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
    - Speech to UBC Arts students, 1992; F-16-6-1-0-247 (Archival box - standard 16-40)
  - Publications correspondence, 1952 - 1992; F-16-6-2; 25 cm of textual records 7 photographs: black and white; 20x25 cm; Physical description: 7 photographs located in F-16-6-2-1
    Subseries consists of correspondence arising from the creation and publication of Dallas Smythe's various publications and presentations. Series includes correspondence regarding Smythe's research in television content studies, pay TV, telecommunications regulations, telecommunications training for individuals in developing countries, the political economy of communications, and other related topics. Subseries also includes correspondence regarding the publication of Smythe's book, Dependency Road.
    Correspondence relating to Smythe's New York television content studies includes some photographs produced during those studies.
    - New York television study No. 1, 1952; F-16-6-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 16-41)
    - New York television study No. 2, 1952; F-16-6-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 16-41)
    - New York television study No. 3, 1952 - 1953; F-16-6-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 16-41)
    - Book on the political economy of communications, 1954 - 1956; F-16-6-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 16-41)
    - Pay TV, 1954 - 1958; F-16-6-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 16-41)